One Pace Premium
Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
Now raise your hands up! Sing your dreams out loud.
Always stand up! Raise our unyielding flag.
So many obstacles are already behind us!
Now let's keep moving forward! Hands up!!
"I'm almost there, just a little further and I'll have the answer."
That's what I believed as I sailed into this new world.
That's right, the pieces of our dreams are joined together as one.
We're connected by unwavering bonds, let's head for a bright future!
Now raise your hands up! Sing your dreams out loud.
Always stand up! Raise our unyielding flag.
So many obstacles are already behind us!
Now let's keep moving forward!
Always look up!
Keep your head held high!
Always step up!
Fly over the waves!
Our dreams have been carefully joined together.
Now let's head for the future!
We drift forward, riding the waves,
meeting people and saying goodbye, then doing it again,
all under this flag...
Pain I don't want to forget is kept in my heart.
There was a day when I softly carved it there.
I won't let anyone take my freedom.
I grasp it tightly in my hands!
Now raise your hands up! Sing your dreams out loud.
Always stand up! Raise our unyielding flag.
So many obstacles are already behind us!
Now let's keep moving forward!
Always look up!
Keep your head held high!
Always step up!
Fly over the waves!
Our dreams have been carefully joined together.
Now let's head for the future!
G-5's Sacrifice and
the Betrayal of the Vice Admiral!
What's this?
What the hell is going on!?
Why aren't the G-5 marines by the main entrance?
Why can't I see any solidified bodies on the display?
Shinokuni's public experiment is nothing without them!
Where's the Straw Hats, Law, and Smoker? Didn't they all die properly?
Any thoughts, Vergo?
There's only one answer.
Those guys aren't in the cage anymore.
My G-5 marines are a bunch of violent idiots.
There's no way they'd be able to escape that gas on their own.
Meaning the Straw Hats escaped from the cage and then helped all the G-5 marines get away.
What did you say!?
Master!
What's wrong?
The pirate Straw Hat Luffy is leading the whole enemy force
through Building-A's lobby, and they're pushing even further inside!
What!? They're inside!?
How can they have got through that solid shutter!?
How did they get out of the cage!?
We don't know!
Whatever the case, having Law free is not good.
Depending on his goal here I may have to kill him myself.
It seems that both the Straw Hat crew and the marines are heading for the escape passage!
What should I do!?
It looks as though everyone's safe for now. That's a relief.
I don't know who gave me this piece of paper,
but did they actually mean that Luffy and the others could escape on their own?
I found out the drug's composition and I've got sedatives now, too.
Wait, which way should I go!?
What are my soldiers doing?
The guards in Building-A are responding to the attack!
The main force is making battle preparations at the post near the back of Building-B!
It's pretty clear that they just want to escape from this island,
in which case they'll be taking a straight path towards Building-R and Gate-66!
I'm not gonna let that happen! Close the walkway between Building-A and Building-B!
Closing this gate will isolate Building-A.
Then we can destroy Building-A and let Shinokuni flood inside!
What? If we do that then our guards will also be—
Never mind that, just do it!
Don't forget to deploy the Surveillance Transponder Snails!
But, Master...
The experiment needs a fresh start for the Brokers to see it properly.
They've yet to see the true extent of my scientific genius!
What're you going to do, Vergo?
You'd be lucky to catch even the small fry in a trap like that.
You're not the only one with something to lose if Law and Smoker aren't caught here, Caesar.
I can't allow you to act alone. I will cut every last one of them down.
Huh? That's odd, my sword is gone.
You're not a swordsman though, are you?
That's right, I'm not a swordsman.
Well then, I'll go and crush those little bastards.
Laboratory Building A
You ain't getting through here, Straw Hat!
I am Machete Run, former pirate and gatekeeper of Building B!
In the name of Master Caesar, scientist of love!
You don't have animal legs! That's lame!
What kinda centaur are you anyway!?
Spider!
Outta my way!
Connecting Passage for Building A & B
What a huge passage!
Law, what's that alarm sounding for?
It's the warning sound that this building's gate is closing and blocking the only path into Building B.
What!?
He's probably trying to lock us all out.
You should quickly move your men to the back.
I dunno what Trafalgar Law meant when he said we've got a two hour time limit,
but we're not gonna let you slip away from us, Straw Hats! You ain't goin' anywhere!
Don't even try it!
Get out of our way!
That's hot!
That's cold!
Nice! Three reliable swordsmen!
Sorry for asking you to carry us all, Brownbeard.
It's no bother, but why did you guys bring that dragon along?
We were only holding onto him since we thought that he could fly us away from the gas,
but he didn't fly at all.
Yeah, he can't fly right now because he's been injected with sedatives.
Still, bringing him into the laboratory may prove to be problematic.
Is he dangerous? He has a pretty cute face though.
We won't get this chance again! Take them out!
We'll get all the credit!
I'm pretty sure I warned you guys about that!
C-Captain-chan!?
Oh, so you're a captain now are you, little miss look-alike?
You've still got no fighting spirit!
Fine, run on ahead.
G-5, we don't have time for fighting right now! Please, hurry to the passage at the back!
There's only one gate in this building and it's starting to close! Caesar's trying to lock us all in here!
If we don't head for that gate we'll all be trapped on Punk Hazard! Quickly, head for the back now!
T-This is bad! Let's get moving, do as Tashigi-chan says, guys!
Carry the wounded!
It's a straight line! Aim for the gate!
What a terrible thing to do.
Robin, where have you been?
Robin-chan!
I had to do a little favor for Luffy.
Anyway, did you hear what that marine said!? Keep going, Brownybeard! Move faster!
No way, I'm going flat out as it is!
I'm so sick of running!
What was that? A complaint?
It wasn't!
I'm not a samurai so I'll just say it!
I've had enough of this!
Hey, why is Brownbeard with those pirates!?
Do you think that bastard might've betrayed Master!?
Master is our savior!
Just keep running! We're in trouble, too!
Let's move it, G-5!
It really is about to close!
Move it, move it!
Experiment cannon, standby!
Laboratory Exterior
Target is set as the outer wall of Building A, Third Laboratory!
Is that wall breaking!?
W-Wait, seriously!?
You're kidding!
Run! Just run!
Shut up!
Help me!
Hey!
Get through the gate!
Get inside or you're dead!
Alright, we made it!
So we have!
Just barely!
Huh!? Captain-chan just came flying in!
I'm glad you're safe, but why were you flying?
Please move aside! There're still marines out there!
You mustn't! It's already filled with gas!
Please move, the gate'll close soon!
You mustn't!
Let me go! They're still out there! Let me go!
The gate's almost closed already!
Smoker-san left them in my care! I will protect them all!
Now please move aside!
It's no use, Captain-chan, it's too late!
Well done, guys! We've safely received our precious captain from you!
What utter scum! Still, far too many of them survived!
I won't let them escape. Not a single one!
Connecting passage for buildings A & B
He's sacrificed the laboratory to let the gas inside.
Hey, pick up the pace!
You guys! When did all of you get on my back!? It's getting too heavy for me!
I'm sorry, but you'll have to stick it out a little longer. There's no other choice.
We're...
really tired and we can't be bothered to run anymore.
That's a terrible reason! Get off me!
You are called Brownbeard, correct?
Forgive me, but I simply must rescue my son, Momonosuke, as soon as possible.
However, I've already done a lot of running and I can't actually be bothered to do any more.
Get off me you stupid bastards!
It's pretty hot with this coat on inside the laboratory.
Yeah, you can hang it over here.
Don't make yourselves at home on people's backs! If you're not hurt then you can run yourselves!
I'm feeling a little peckish.
I never hunger, for I have the stomach of a samurai.
Brownbeard-san, do you have anything to eat?
Shut up! The minute we reach one of the soldiers' posts I'm gonna shake you all off my back!
Connecting passage for buildings A & B
Captain-chan, We've gotta get moving!
We thought Punk Hazard was locked down, but that guy was making weapons of mass destruction here!
We gotta act before the whole world's affected!
We've gotta get off the island and alert Navy Headquarters!
If we can't make it back alive to the main force then what did those guys just sacrifice their lives for!?
I'm sorry.
Let's go!
Wait a minute.
Something's on the ceiling!
What is that thing!?
I think it was with those Straw Hat guys earlier!
It looks like some kinda lizard!
I've heard stories about this. About how Punk Hazard has real dragons on it.
Doctor Vegapunk artificially created these mythical beasts to protect the island.
It didn't look so scary a minute ago!
He dodged!?
T-T-That's steel!
If you get bitten by jaws like that...
Everyone, get moving to Building B now!
It flies, breathes fire and chews steel!
What kinda monster is this!?
What happened?
It's gone.
It ran away?
Something spooked him.
Captain Tashigi, this is awesome!
Our strongest backup is here on Punk Hazard!
The Vice Admiral has come to save us!
Vergo!
Vice Admiral Smokey and Vice Admiral Vergo! The two heads of the G-5 are here!
We're gonna be invincible now!
No!
Alright, we're saved now!
Run! All of you, run away!
V-Vice Admiral Vergo, did those guys do something wrong?
Even if they needed a beating, getting hit by your Finger Gun can kill!
Welcome.
I've heard much about you, Commodore Smoker, it's nice to meet you.
My G-5 boys are as rough and stupid as they come, but once you get to know them
they're not as bad as the rest of the world says.
Before too long you'll come to think of them fondly.
Where's Vice Admiral Vergo?
Don't worry about it. Vice Admiral Vergo has to hurry back home from time to time.
His younger sister is pretty sick.
Are you guys really the Navy!?
I am sorry.
I'm entirely responsible for the actions of my subordinates.
Oh, is that right? Well then, you'd better take full responsibility right now!
Bitch!
Don't get carried away!
I understand. I'll make sure they do whatever is needed to make you happy.
Vice Admiral Vergo, regarding the reports of kidnapped children we spoke of the other day...
Yes, I investigated, but they appear to have simply been accidents at sea. The reports were incorrect.
Incorrect?
It's hard for any parent to accept the death of their child,
that's why they still cling to the idea of a kidnapping so they can continue to live in hope.
You'll come to understand that when you become a parent someday.
Is that really how it is?
Yes, that's really how it is.
Everyone, get back! He's not the man you used to know!
The whole damn time, this guy—
Captain-chan!
This guy's an impostor!
Vergo-san would never do something like this to our Captain-chan!
Yeah! Is that a disguise!? Are you an ability user!?
Bastard, how dare you imitate Vice Admiral Vergo!
Vice Admiral Vergo even took lowlife marines like us under his wing, he's a man of humanity and justice!
Stop imitating him!
You're goin' down, you copycat bastard!
I can't even speak!
Please, just stop!
Help us, Smoker-san!
There's a lady...
Who's there?
...calling out to me!
One of the Straw Hats!
Why's a pirate helping us?
I could hear a lady's tears falling to the ground.
Building B Interior
Sanji's expression changed and then he just flew off!
I felt a strange presence suddenly appear back there. Just forget it.
Is that...
It's the dragon from earlier!
Wait, he looks a little different.
His eyes!
Looks like his sedatives have worn off like I thought.
On top of that, he's one of the newer, smaller and more advanced types.
They're more agile and have tougher bodies.
Building B Central Staircase
I'm gonna capture Caesar!
What about you?
I've got a score to settle with Vergo.
Will he be with Caesar?
I doubt it, now stay out of my way!
Dammit, get back here!
Caesar's Laboratory
What the hell is that Vergo bastard doing!?
The G-5 are a necessary part of my experiment!
There's no damn point if they aren't all killed by Shinokuni! That idiot!
Since it's come to this, block off the passage in front of the G-5 then let the gas flow in behind them!
But, Vergo is still in there.
You think I care about that idiot's life!? Do it now!
Building B 3rd floor
Near Biscuit Room
Biscuit Room is this way!
Let's go!
You ready?
No, I'm not! Can't you wait a minute!?
I've been running so damn fast I set the ground on fire!
But you, flying through the air on that fluffy cloud of smoke, that's gotta be cheating!
Alright, you ready?
Wait a moment! Hey, didn't I already say wait a minute!?
When I say "let's go" we'll go.
I've just gotta compose myself.
Hey! I haven't even said "let's go" yet!
You listening? Vergo is my enemy!
Yeah, I know. Caesar is mine! Keep your damn hands off him!
Ah, this one's mine!
You ain't gettin' away this time, Caesar!
Translation & initial timing, Kousei Fansubs
Timing, Galaxy 9000
Quality checking, Sewil
Soundtracking, MaideV and Halee
Editing, Sewil
Title card artist, sergiart.deviantart.com